CURRICULUM VITAE

RITU SEHRAWAT

New Ashok Nagar New Delhi

7668624005 | r.choudhary.itu@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A result-oriented IT Professional with around **4.3 Years** of total experience in Digital Marketing and implementation of web application.

Further in my 4.3 years of exploratory journey I experienced implementing a wide array of digital marketing techniques to promote brand awareness, increase customers engagement, maintain and increase rank of the keyword as well as website in order to get the customer traffic and meet sales and brand objectives.

SKILLS

- Web 2.0
- HTML
- SMO
- Google Analytic
- Webmaster tool
- Ahrefs
- SEMrush
- Local Broken Link checking

- On Page Optimization and Off Page Optimization
- Monitoring and Monthly Reporting
- Microsoft Office
- Competitors SEO performance Analysis
- Website performance Monitoring
- Ability to Handle various SEO tools
- Keyword Research, Competitor Analysis

WORK HISTORY

31West Global Services

Sr. SEO Specialist | Bengaluru, Karnataka | Aug 2021- Present

About Company – 31West is a leading provider of Outsourced Customer Support & Technology Consulting Services. Our delivery center operates 24/7/365. We specialize in high-quality, cost-effective Call Center, Help Desk & Back Office Services to small and medium businesses in the US. We also have a strong presence in Canada, UK, & Western Europe.

Roles and Responsibilities -

- Hands-on experience in Handling On page and off page activities.
- Communicate with content writers effectively to plan web content.

- Coordinate with the technical, developers and designers.
- Hands-on experience with Creating infographics also creates PDFs.
- Analyzed google analytic and created reports based on the meaningful insights.
- Monitored scheduled and unscheduled algorithm changes to the major search engine.

SEO Analyst at Sagenext Infotech LLC, Noida

SEO Analyst | Noida, UP | Feb 2021 - July 2021

About Company – Founded in 2009, Sagenext Infotech is a US-based company with headquarters located in Augusta, Georgia. Delivering superior levels of shared and dedicated hosting services to small and medium businesses, accounting professionals, bookkeepers, and CPAs, the company has cemented its position as a frontline tax and accounting software hosting provider over the years in North America and the UK.

Roles and Responsibilities -

- Hands-on experience in Handling On page and off page activities.
- Communicate with content writers effectively to plan web content.
- Coordinate with the technical, developers and designers.
- Hands-on experience with Creating infographics.
- Analyzed google analytic and created reports based on the meaningful insights.
- Monitored scheduled and unscheduled algorithm changes to the major search engine.

99 Fusion Technosoft pvt. Lmt.

Sr. SEO Executive & HR | Noida, UP | Sep 2017 - Feb 2021

About Company – 99Fusion · Online Products · Web Solutions · Design Agency · Create beautiful interactive products and integrated web solutions. We create innovative products for web and Mobile. Experts in App development, React, Angular, WordPress themes & plugins, E commerce solutions, SEO and Google Analytics/Adwords/Adsense.

Roles and Responsibilities -

- Experience in the field of SEO, SMO.
- 1 year experience in the field of HR Executive to get the best resources for the organization as well as making a healthy work culture.
- Communicate with content writers effectively to plan web content and explain to them vital details that should be included within the advertisement.
- Coordinate with the technicians, developers and designers to set up a new website.
- Analyze the performance of the web advertisement in increasing sales of the organization.
- Make changes if necessary, to enhance the reach and effectiveness of the web advertisement.

Seoczar Pvt. Lmt.

SEO Intern | Noida, UP | Feb 2017 - Sep 2017

About Company – SEOCZAR IT Services Pvt Ltd is one of India's finest Search Engine Optimization Company, located in Noida. It was initially established in 2013 and officially started in October 2015. We help aspiring businesses just like yours to generate long-term profits by driving maximum web traffic, connecting with customers worldwide, and growing overall sales.

Roles and Responsibilities -

- Do all off page activities.
- Experience in the field of SEO as an Internee.
- Blog Posting and Pdf creation.
- Experienced in Creating infographics.

EDUCATION

*** Completed 6 months industrial training of Web Designing at Cetpa InfoTech Private Limited, Noida

B.A in English

Meerut, Uttar Pradesh

Intermediate School form CBSE

Royal Public School

Shamli, Uttar Pradesh

High School form CBSE

Royal Public School

Shamli, Uttar Pradesh

STRENGTH

- Strong Will Power.
- Flexibility.
- Punctual.
- Hard Working.
- Management
- Leadership
- Communication

HOBBIES

- Listening To Music
- Badminton
- Surf Internet
- Observe to the Natural Places